<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog</id>
    <title>GameVault Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://gamevau.lt/blog"/>
    <subtitle>GameVault Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://gamevau.lt/img/logo.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GameVault+ out now]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/04/14/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/04/14/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p>
<p>We're thrilled to announce that the early access phase of GameVault+ has concluded, and we're officially launching it today! It's been an incredible journey from the inception of GameVault to where we are now, and we couldn't have done it without your amazing support.</p>
<p>GameVault+ is our way of saying thank you to our dedicated supporters while also ensuring the sustainability of our platform. For a small monthly fee, you'll gain access to premium features designed to enhance your gaming experience within GameVault. We're starting with features like animated profile pictures, custom themes, and activation of the GameVault Client API, with more exciting additions planned for the future.</p>
<p>But our work doesn't stop here. We're committed to refining GameVault+ based on your feedback, as well as addressing key areas of improvement in the platform. This includes exploring partnerships with reputable video game databases to enhance our data offerings and refactoring our client application for optimal performance.</p>
<p>And most importantly, we want you, our community, to have a say in the future direction of GameVault. That's why we're opening up the floor for feature suggestions through our Discord channel. Your input will help shape the next big updates to GameVault.</p>
<p>Thank you all for your support and enthusiasm. We're excited to continue this journey with you and to make gaming even more enjoyable for everyone. Stay tuned for more updates, and happy gaming!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="gaming" term="gaming"/>
        <category label="self-hosted" term="self-hosted"/>
        <category label="platform" term="platform"/>
        <category label="DRM-free" term="DRM-free"/>
        <category label="video games" term="video games"/>
        <category label="GameVault" term="GameVault"/>
        <category label="subscription" term="subscription"/>
        <category label="community-driven" term="community-driven"/>
        <category label="updates" term="updates"/>
        <category label="announcement" term="announcement"/>
        <category label="early access" term="early access"/>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
        <category label="features" term="features"/>
        <category label="sustainability" term="sustainability"/>
        <category label="partnerships" term="partnerships"/>
        <category label="Discord" term="Discord"/>
        <category label="feedback" term="feedback"/>
        <category label="improvement" term="improvement"/>
        <category label="development" term="development"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GameVault Client is now available on Windows Phone 7 based on Microsoft Silverlight!]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/04/01/2024-04-01/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/04/01/2024-04-01/"/>
        <updated>2024-04-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Everyone!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Everyone!</p>
<p>The moment you've been waiting for is finally here. We've been working hard on it for months and are thrilled to announce that GameVault Client Application is <strong>now available on Windows Phone 7</strong>, powered by <strong>Microsoft Silverlight</strong>!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Windows Phone" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/winphone-b86bbc15f22660b02f20e840cded2b9c.png" width="655" height="1237" class="img_rGqp"></p>
<p>The Current PC-Version of GameVault will be discontinued soon and will no longer be available to download from the Microsoft Store, as the technology is too new and not well supported yet. We needed a battle-tested framework to ensure compatibility, so we decided to switch to Windows Phone 7 and Silverlight. Also, the mobile platform just has massive market share, compared to PC.</p>
<p>We understand the excitement and anticipation surrounding this release, and we're just as eager as you are to see how this integration will enhance your experience.</p>
<p>With GameVault on your Windows Phone 7 device, you can carry your favorite games with you wherever you go. Whether you're battling fierce foes, exploring vast virtual worlds, or simply passing the time with a quick puzzle game, GameVault ensures that the thrill of gaming is always at your fingertips.</p>
<p>Thanks to the seamless integration with Microsoft Silverlight, navigating through your game library has never been smoother or more intuitive. The Metro Live Tiles add a touch of elegance to the user interface, making it a joy to browse through your collection and discover new games.</p>
<p>And the best part? This is just the beginning. Our team is already hard at work on further enhancements and features, including the highly anticipated Holodeck edition of GameVault aswell as the new integrated "Bird Feeding Timer" feature, that automatically warns you when your pets are about to starve.</p>
<p>We're incredibly excited to embark on this journey with you and to continue pushing the boundaries of innovation. So what are you waiting for? Head over to the Windows Phone Store and migrate today to start your gaming adventure!</p>
<p>Happy gaming... and April Fools!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="April Fools" term="April Fools"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing GameVault+ (coming soon)]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/03/28/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/03/28/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Everyone!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Everyone!</p>
<p>It feels like it's been ages since we last caught up regarding the development of <a href="https://gamevau.lt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameVault (the self-hostable platform for drm-free videogames)</a>, but trust me, the silence from our end doesn't mean we've been slacking off. In fact, quite the opposite has been happening behind the scenes.</p>
<p>When my friend and I first launched this application, it was born out of a simple need for a solution to a problem we thought was very particular and only for ourselves. Having a steam-like platform for game files lying on my home server.</p>
<p>We never imagined it would resonate with others or find its own place in the market. Frankly, we thought it might end up just another forgotten repository on GitHub, gathering virtual dust with no one paying it any mind.</p>
<p>But boy, were we wrong. The response to our app was unexpectedly large and overwhelming. Thousands of people are using GameVault today, and it seems there's quite a demand out there for the exact product we've been building.</p>
<p>We’re a small indie team of two and despite juggling multiple jobs, we've poured our hearts and souls into this project during our spare times, striving to offer a self-hosted alternative to the gaming platforms out there. And while we've received some generous donations (<em>shoutout to our two loyal monthly donors btw – you know who you are, and we're endlessly grateful!</em>), it's clear that relying solely on sporadic tips isn't sustainable for the long term and we need financial support to maintain our services and justify our time investment towards our families.</p>
<p>So, it's time for a slight change. We're thrilled to announce the upcoming release of a new version of our client application, complete with an <strong>optional</strong> subscription model we're calling...</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="gamevault"><a href="https://gamevau.lt/docs/gamevault-plus/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameVault+</a><a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/03/28/#gamevault" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to gamevault" title="Direct link to gamevault">​</a></h2>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="what-is-gamevault">What is GameVault+?<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/03/28/#what-is-gamevault" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What is GameVault+?" title="Direct link to What is GameVault+?">​</a></h2>
<p>First, to clear some of the confusion:</p>
<p><strong>No, this is not some shady scammy "We're going enterprise" rugpull</strong>.
The core of GameVaults upcoming features and the features you enjoyed until now will always remain free. Additionally the system is <a href="https://gamevau.lt/docs/gamevault-plus/introduction/#what-if-i-cant-afford-gamevault" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">designed to be easily bypassed if you can't or dont want to afford it.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Phalcode/gamevault-app/issues/151" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">It was long planned on our board and well discussed within our community</a>. Think of <a href="https://gamevau.lt/docs/gamevault-plus/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameVault+</a> as our way of saying "thank you" to our supporters and to motivate them to support us regularly. To be more specific, it's us giving back some goodie-features that are not necessarily needed to use GameVault back to our supporters, while they help us keep the lights on here at Phalcode.</p>
<p>With GameVault+, you'll gain access to premium nice-to-have features designed to enhance your GameVault experience, all for a small monthly fee of €4,99 monthly or €49.90 anually.</p>
<p>Currently, these features include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Uploading animated profile pictures</li>
<li>Applying Custom Themes</li>
<li>Activation of the GameVault Client API (CLI, URI, and NamedPipe Interfaces Used for client integrations with 3rd party tools like Playnite)</li>
</ul>
<p>But there are more to come! We will be enhancing this offering with more features, whenever we see room for it, as GameVault+ subscribers are the ones, who keep this project alive.</p>
<p>All details and a Q&amp;A are on the <a href="https://gamevau.lt/docs/gamevault-plus/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameVault+ page</a>.</p>
<p><strong>We'll be rolling out this new product today to our early access users first</strong> to get the product and the infrastructure around it tested, tweaking and refining it based on your feedback before making it available to everyone. It's an exciting new chapter for us, and we can't wait to have you along for the ride.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="so-whats-next">So what's next?<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2024/03/28/#so-whats-next" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to So what's next?" title="Direct link to So what's next?">​</a></h2>
<p>We will polish the rough edges of GameVault+ and bring it to life in the next few weeks, hopefully. You will probably already see some documentation on this website for it. Keep in mind, this is all a work in progress, and we will announce the final release soon.</p>
<p>After that, we will need to urgently find a solution to our heavy reliance on the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1100920639667306496/1134496308846137404/1217726870959820861" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">degrading and unmaintained RAWG Database</a>. We are already in contact for potential partnerships with Video-Game Databases.</p>
<p>Finally, we will need to do some refactoring of our client application's architecture.</p>
<p>But stay tuned because once all of this is done, the Next Big Feature we'll be focusing on will be open for <strong>the community to decide</strong> in <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">our #polls channel on Discord</a>. So make sure to join "The Council" to get notified and vote on your most desired feature.</p>
<p>Thank you all for supporting us and looking forward to seeing you all on our next updates!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="startup" term="startup"/>
        <category label="software" term="software"/>
        <category label="gaming" term="gaming"/>
        <category label="GameVault" term="GameVault"/>
        <category label="subscription model" term="subscription model"/>
        <category label="development" term="development"/>
        <category label="community" term="community"/>
        <category label="announcement" term="announcement"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Join the GameVault Early-Access Program Now!]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/12/09/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/12/09/"/>
        <updated>2023-12-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, Guys!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey, Guys!</p>
<p>For the upcoming large UI update of GameVault, we're launching a brand new GameVault Early-Access Program, and we want <strong>YOU</strong> to be a part of it!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="whats-the-early-access-program">What's the Early-Access Program?<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/12/09/#whats-the-early-access-program" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What's the Early-Access Program?" title="Direct link to What's the Early-Access Program?">​</a></h2>
<p>Early-Access is your golden ticket to test-drive upcoming GameVault updates before anyone else. You'll be part of an exclusive group and get a sneak peek into the latest features, but here's the deal – it might not be as stable as our regular releases and you need to interact with us. Your feedback will help us fine-tune everything before the big release for everyone else.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="how-to-join">How to Join<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/12/09/#how-to-join" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How to Join" title="Direct link to How to Join">​</a></h2>
<p>📋<!-- --> Complete the <a href="https://forms.gle/RQvEGfWeUFPBCUaG6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Application Form</a><br>
<!-- -->📅<!-- --> The first early-access phase kicks off on December 17 and lasts for one week.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="prerequisites">Prerequisites<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/12/09/#prerequisites" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Prerequisites" title="Direct link to Prerequisites">​</a></h2>
<p>💬<!-- --> Active participation in the designated Discord channel.<br>
<!-- -->🎮<!-- --> GameVault installed from the Microsoft Store with a Microsoft Account logged in. If not, grab it <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PCKDV76GL75" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.<br>
<!-- -->🚀<!-- --> A GameVault Server running the <strong>phalcode/gamevault-backend<!-- -->:early-access</strong> image. (Only run this if you are accepted as a Tester as it could break things!)</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="important-note">Important Note<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/12/09/#important-note" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Important Note" title="Direct link to Important Note">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There are only a limited number of slots in the Early-Access Program. Supporters and Trusted Members are prioritized.</li>
<li>If you're accepted and later found not meeting the requirements, you might be removed from future testing and the next applicant on our list gets the opportunity.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://forms.gle/RQvEGfWeUFPBCUaG6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apply here!</a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Gaming" term="Gaming"/>
        <category label="GameVault" term="GameVault"/>
        <category label="Early Access" term="Early Access"/>
        <category label="UI Update" term="UI Update"/>
        <category label="Beta Testing" term="Beta Testing"/>
        <category label="Community Feedback" term="Community Feedback"/>
        <category label="Exclusive Preview" term="Exclusive Preview"/>
        <category label="Microsoft Store" term="Microsoft Store"/>
        <category label="Discord" term="Discord"/>
        <category label="Gaming Servers" term="Gaming Servers"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Look Back and a Glimpse Forward]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/11/20/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/11/20/"/>
        <updated>2023-11-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello,</p>
<p>It's been a while since we caught up here, but if you've been following the action on <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a>, you're up to speed. Nevertheless, this blog remains your spot for the key updates and announements.</p>
<p>Let's dive into what's been happening with GameVault since release and what's on the horizon. We've hit version 9 on the backend and 1.7 on the frontend, showcasing our commitment to continuous improvement.</p>
<p>Alongside the usual optimizations and bug fixes, we've been paying a lot of attention to your feature requests and implemented a bunch of them.</p>
<p>Here's the highlight reel:</p>
<ul>
<li>Auto Extraction and Installation of Videogames</li>
<li>Uninstalling Games through GameVault</li>
<li>Uploading Images</li>
<li>Support for more Archive Formats</li>
<li>Bandwidth Control Features</li>
<li>Database Backups &amp; Restorations</li>
<li>Crash Reporting</li>
<li>Random Game Finder</li>
</ul>
<p>So, what's cooking now? We asked for your top three desired features recently, and here are the results:</p>
<ol>
<li>UI Redesign for the Library and Installations Tab</li>
<li>Support for ROMS and Emulators</li>
<li>Support for extra files like Soundtracks, Mods, etc.</li>
</ol>
<p>By the way, if you want to take part in polls like this in the future aswell, make sure to become a council member on <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a>!</p>
<p>Right now we're knee-deep in redesigning the Library, the heart of our application. Big changes are on the way, waving goodbye to the installations tab and ushering in a sleeker UI for Library, Game View, and Game Settings.</p>
<p>Here are some sneak peeks and mockups: (still work in progress):</p>
<ol>
<li>Library (Mockup)
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Filters" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/filters-f2a63aa5f8026620c96a6af4d668e8de.png" width="1896" height="1080" class="img_rGqp">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Empty States" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/emptystates-cac04f51fc52e209e202e0611b7fc9ce.png" width="1896" height="1080" class="img_rGqp"></li>
<li>Library (current implementation)
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Library" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/library-23677b063b1eec718776e44519f449fd.png" width="960" height="520" class="img_rGqp"></li>
<li>Game (Mockup)
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Game View" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/game-1a2301146090a980e3af454aa57abb22.png" width="1896" height="1080" class="img_rGqp"></li>
<li>Game Settings (Mockup)
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Game Settings" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/settings-ec331d2e53857decc5abb85f44855896.png" width="1080" height="792" class="img_rGqp"></li>
</ol>
<p>Remember, these are teasers. Anything can look different once it ships. There's a lot of work left, and we're on it. To be technical here: Most of these modern controls require us to rewrite WPF Controls from the core. On the backend, we're not slacking either – tons of end-to-end tests are being written to ensure our app's reliability.</p>
<p>Excited about the new UI or got something to say? Head over to <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> and spill the beans!</p>
<p>We're eager to wrap up these tasks and ship the update out to you guys.</p>
<p>We also wanted to mention we've already crossed 2000 GameVault users with a growing engaged <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> community of 350 members!</p>
<p>And your donations help keeping the lights on, though we're not rolling in dough just yet. Every penny counts, and we're truly grateful. Thanks a lot. ❤️</p>
<p>Help us promote GameVault among fellow self-hosters. Your efforts could inspire a bored developer to join and contribute to our project!</p>
<p>Stay tuned for the UI update – we'll be back in touch soon.</p>
<p>Until then, happy gaming! 🎮</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Game Development" term="Game Development"/>
        <category label="Software Updates" term="Software Updates"/>
        <category label="Gaming Community" term="Gaming Community"/>
        <category label="UI Redesign" term="UI Redesign"/>
        <category label="Development Milestones" term="Development Milestones"/>
        <category label="Tech Progress" term="Tech Progress"/>
        <category label="Future Features" term="Future Features"/>
        <category label="GameVault Journey" term="GameVault Journey"/>
        <category label="Coding Chronicle" term="Coding Chronicle"/>
        <category label="November Update" term="November Update"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Please help us prioritize!]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/29/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/29/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello everyone!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone!</p>
<p>We hope you're all doing well. We wanted to take a moment to express our heartfelt gratitude for the flood of feature requests and bug reports that have been pouring into our issue trackers. Your enthusiasm and dedication to making GameVault even better are truly inspiring to us.</p>
<p>As many of you may already know, GameVault is a passion project for us, and while we are mostly convinced by your fantastic ideas, it may take some time for us to implement them. Our team meetings happen in our free time, and although we genuinely want to incorporate your suggestions into our roadmap, we are limited by the time and capacity we can dedicate to the project. Moreover, we want to ensure that the features we develop are refined, polished, and also the most desired in the users' opinions, which adds to the timeline.</p>
<p>We believe that collaboration with our incredible community is the key to success, and that's why we want to introduce you to our Roadmap. It displays all new issues, planned tasks we want to work on, and all the ongoing work in a well-organized Kanban Board. <a href="https://github.com/orgs/Phalcode/projects/4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You can find it right here.</a></p>
<p>To ensure that GameVault's development aligns better with your needs, we kindly request your active participation. By voting on GitHub with a Thumbs Up or a Thumbs Down on new and planned issues, you can help us prioritize them effectively. We value your opinion: What features do you feel are most crucial? What aspects of the platform do you find most bothersome? What issues do you see as unnecessary or bloated? Your input will mainly shape the direction we take.</p>
<p>If you're eager to go the extra mile and actively contribute to shaping GameVault further, we invite you to <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">join our Discord community</a> and becoming a "Council Member". By becoming a "Council Member" and enabling Poll Notifications under "#Channels &amp; Roles", you will have a direct say in the future of GameVault because you will get notifications about opinion polls we run from time to time.</p>
<p>We cannot stress enough how much we appreciate your involvement in our endeavor to create the ultimate gaming experience for all of you. Your passion and feedback are invaluable, and we are committed to making GameVault the best it can be, together.</p>
<p>Thank you for being part of this amazing journey with us!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="community" term="community"/>
        <category label="GameVault" term="GameVault"/>
        <category label="development" term="development"/>
        <category label="roadmap" term="roadmap"/>
        <category label="collaboration" term="collaboration"/>
        <category label="feedback" term="feedback"/>
        <category label="GitHub" term="GitHub"/>
        <category label="voting" term="voting"/>
        <category label="features" term="features"/>
        <category label="platform" term="platform"/>
        <category label="Kanban Board" term="Kanban Board"/>
        <category label="Discord" term="Discord"/>
        <category label="Council Member" term="Council Member"/>
        <category label="polls" term="polls"/>
        <category label="gaming experience" term="gaming experience"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating 600+ Installations and announcing the upcoming big feature]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p>
<p>We're excited to share some great news with you all! GameVault has reached a small milestone with over 600 official installations of our GameVault Client Application. What's even more amazing is that around 200 dedicated users, a third of these installations, have joined our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> community to connect, chat, and share their experiences.</p>
<p>We want to express our immense gratitude for your incredible support, feedback, and love for GameVault. Your ongoing encouragement inspires us to push boundaries and enhance your gaming experience. We're thrilled to announce that an awesome update is being worked on right now - the highly anticipated release of GameVault's Installation Pipeline!</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="gamevaults-installation-pipeline">GameVault's Installation Pipeline<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/#gamevaults-installation-pipeline" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to GameVault's Installation Pipeline" title="Direct link to GameVault's Installation Pipeline">​</a></h4>
<p>The Installation Pipeline is designed to revolutionize how you install and manage your games. It was suggested by members on our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a>. We understand the challenges of navigating through different installation processes, especially for family members who may not be tech-savvy. With the Installation Pipeline, our goal is to simplify the entire process and make it user-friendly. Whether you're an experienced gamer or not, this update will make installing games easier for you.</p>
<p>You can read the details <a href="https://github.com/Phalcode/gamevault-app/issues/18" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here on the GitHub issue</a>.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for its upcoming release, and to be among the first to try out this awesome feature, make sure to subscribe to the <code>@Updates</code> Role on our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a> , if you haven't already. We'll ping you as soon as it's live!</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="join-us-on-lemmy">Join us on Lemmy<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/#join-us-on-lemmy" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Join us on Lemmy" title="Direct link to Join us on Lemmy">​</a></h4>
<p>To further connect with our amazing community, we're excited to announce the launch of our <a href="https://lemmy.world/c/phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official Lemmy community</a>. From now on, we'll also regularly share new blog posts there, providing you with more ways to stay informed and engaged. Join the Lemmy forum and become part of the growing GameVault community!</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="share-gamevault-with-others">Share GameVault with Others<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/#share-gamevault-with-others" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Share GameVault with Others" title="Direct link to Share GameVault with Others">​</a></h4>
<p>As we celebrate this milestone and eagerly anticipate more exciting updates, we invite you to spread the word about GameVault among your friends, family, and gaming or self-hosting communities. Your personal recommendations and referrals have played a significant role in our journey so far, and we believe they'll continue to do so in the future.</p>
<p>We want to express our heartfelt appreciation for the feature requests, discussions, and invaluable help on our GitHub. Your support and collaborative efforts help a lot.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="support-us">Support Us<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/#support-us" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Support Us" title="Direct link to Support Us">​</a></h4>
<p>As we move forward, we kindly ask for your continued support. GameVault's success is currently solely built upon our incredible community, and your encouragement is what fuels us. If you love our app and believe in our vision, please consider supporting us in any way you can. It could even be something simple like a rating on the Microsoft Store. Your backing empowers us to keep our hard work going.</p>
<p>We're eagerly looking forward to celebrating more achievements with all of you.</p>
<p>Stay tuned, stay connected, and let's continue this journey together!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="GameVault milestone" term="GameVault milestone"/>
        <category label="official installations" term="official installations"/>
        <category label="Discord community growth" term="Discord community growth"/>
        <category label="gratitude" term="gratitude"/>
        <category label="feedback" term="feedback"/>
        <category label="love for GameVault" term="love for GameVault"/>
        <category label="upcoming update" term="upcoming update"/>
        <category label="Installation Pipeline" term="Installation Pipeline"/>
        <category label="simplifying game installation" term="simplifying game installation"/>
        <category label="GitHub issue" term="GitHub issue"/>
        <category label="subscription to Updates role" term="subscription to Updates role"/>
        <category label="Lemmy community launch" term="Lemmy community launch"/>
        <category label="sharing blog posts" term="sharing blog posts"/>
        <category label="spreading the word" term="spreading the word"/>
        <category label="support request" term="support request"/>
        <category label="continued support" term="continued support"/>
        <category label="celebration of achievements" term="celebration of achievements"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Migrations are finally completed]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/20/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/20/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey folks,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey folks,</p>
<p>Great news. We've successfully migrated our App name in its entirety and will resume advertising as soon as it's published on the Microsoft Store.</p>
<p>Just a heads up, there might be a surge of new users joining the <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> server due to us promoting GameVault across all available platforms now.</p>
<p>You're welcome to join in and spread the word about GameVault with your friends, family, social network, or colleagues!</p>
<p><strong>Let's decipher the mystery behind the new logo:</strong>
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="logo" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/logo-text-and-image-sbs-6a7a4b169bd1cf62f643469e715ae759.png" width="1000" height="103" class="img_rGqp"></p>
<ul>
<li>The Box represents a Vault with a Keyhole, but it also symbolizes a game dice.</li>
<li>The Keyhole represents a Keyhole, and simultaneously signifies a game piece.</li>
</ul>
<p>Did you find the logo concept creative? Share your thoughts on <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">discord</a>!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="app name migration" term="app name migration"/>
        <category label="Microsoft Store publication" term="Microsoft Store publication"/>
        <category label="surge of new users" term="surge of new users"/>
        <category label="Discord server promotion" term="Discord server promotion"/>
        <category label="spreading the word" term="spreading the word"/>
        <category label="logo deciphering" term="logo deciphering"/>
        <category label="box representation" term="box representation"/>
        <category label="keyhole representation" term="keyhole representation"/>
        <category label="logo concept discussion" term="logo concept discussion"/>
        <category label="Discord channel" term="Discord channel"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick Migration Update and new Logo]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/19/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/19/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey guys,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys,</p>
<p>We have a brief update on the progress of the name migration.</p>
<p>We've successfully completed the migration of the backend application, which is now accessible as <code>gamevault-backend</code>.</p>
<p>Furthermore, we've migrated the documentation and acquired this domain gamevau.lt. We've set up redirects for our previous domain and the demo server as well.</p>
<p>Lastly we migrated our Subreddit to <a href="https://reddit.com/r/Phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">r/Phalcode</a> and opened up a new community on <a href="https://lemmy.world/c/phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lemmy</a>. All further Updates and discussions regarding GameVault can be found there.</p>
<p>We're nearly finished, you might say.</p>
<p>The only remaining task is the Client Application. We're actively working on it and currently testing the application on our developer edition. Soon, you'll be able to seamlessly update your client with the new name and appearance.</p>
<p>In the meantime, our graphic designer has crafted a fresh logo for our new name, GameVault.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="logo" src="https://gamevau.lt/assets/images/logo-text-and-image-sbs-6a7a4b169bd1cf62f643469e715ae759.png" width="1000" height="103" class="img_rGqp"></p>
<p>To make good use of your time while the migrations are in progress, what do you speculate the new logo represents?</p>
<p>Share your theories in gamevaults #chat channel on <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">discord</a>! We'll reveal the answer and shoutout the winner(s) in the next blog post, once the migration is finalized!</p>
<p>Until then ✌️</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="name migration progress" term="name migration progress"/>
        <category label="backend application migration" term="backend application migration"/>
        <category label="documentation migration" term="documentation migration"/>
        <category label="domain acquisition" term="domain acquisition"/>
        <category label="Subreddit migration" term="Subreddit migration"/>
        <category label="Lemmy community" term="Lemmy community"/>
        <category label="Client Application update" term="Client Application update"/>
        <category label="testing" term="testing"/>
        <category label="new logo" term="new logo"/>
        <category label="speculation" term="speculation"/>
        <category label="Discord channel" term="Discord channel"/>
        <category label="migration finalization" term="migration finalization"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Name]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p>
<p>We are thrilled to announce that the poll for choosing a new name for our app is finally over. The process of transitioning to the new name will commence very soon, and we can't wait to share the exciting updates with you.</p>
<p>But first, let's dive into the poll results and shed some light on the important facts without further delay:</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="summary">Summary<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#summary" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Summary" title="Direct link to Summary">​</a></h2>
<p>In total, 71 people participated in the poll, providing us with valuable data to draw conclusions from. Here's a summary of the key findings:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>52.1% of the community voted against using any terms related to piracy in the app. We understand and respect this choice because it would harm our business and attract the wrong users, as we have no affiliation with piracy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>42.3% of the community voted to recommend the app under a different name but not with its current name. This feedback motivated us to rename the app, confirming that it wasn't just a few critics on Reddit. We want to expand our community to include the families, friends, and colleagues of these people. So please, help us spread the word about the name change!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>36.6% of you said you wouldn't contribute to our app at all solely because of its name, even if you had the opportunity. We depend on these contributions to grow and improve, so we now encourage you to participate!</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Without further ado, here are the top 5 names that emerged as winners in the poll:</p>
<ol>
<li>GameStash (38%)</li>
<li>GameVault (35.2%)</li>
<li>GameShelf (31%)</li>
<li>Harbor (29.6%)</li>
<li>GameHub (28.2%)</li>
</ol>
<p>As mentioned earlier, we conducted the poll without conducting market analysis beforehand. However, we recognized the significance of making an informed decision for the benefit of the community. Consequently, we proceeded to analyze each name after the poll to ensure the chosen name resonates with our vision.</p>
<p>Allow us to share the summarized results of our market analysis:</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="market-analysis">Market Analysis<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#market-analysis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Market Analysis" title="Direct link to Market Analysis">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="1-gamestash">1. GameStash<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#1-gamestash" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1. GameStash" title="Direct link to 1. GameStash">​</a></h3>
<p>Google Search Results: ~33,600<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: gamestash.de</p>
<ul>
<li>There's already an app called <a href="https://gamestash.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameStash</a> that offers similar features to ours.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="2-gamevault">2. GameVault<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#2-gamevault" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2. GameVault" title="Direct link to 2. GameVault">​</a></h3>
<p>Google Search Results: ~800,000<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: gamevau.lt, game-vault.de</p>
<ul>
<li>The term "GameVault" is associated with a popular online casino/gambling application called <a href="https://gamevault999.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameVault999</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="3-gameshelf">3. GameShelf<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#3-gameshelf" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 3. GameShelf" title="Direct link to 3. GameShelf">​</a></h3>
<p>Google Search Results: ~560,000<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: gameshelf.de</p>
<ul>
<li>The name "Gameshelf" is already used by two existing applications. One is a <a href="https://gameshelf.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Board-Game-Collection Viewer</a>, and the other is a <a href="https://gameshelf.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gaming Backlog</a> app.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="4-harbor">4. Harbor<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#4-harbor" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 4. Harbor" title="Direct link to 4. Harbor">​</a></h3>
<p>Google Search Results: ~393,000,000<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: harborapp.de</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>"Harbor" is a very common word, making it challenging to find a suitable domain that aligns with our brand identity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Additionally, there's a well-known app called <a href="https://goharbor.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Harbor on the Market</a> related to Docker/Kubernetes.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="5-gamehub">5. GameHub<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#5-gamehub" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 5. GameHub" title="Direct link to 5. GameHub">​</a></h3>
<p>Google Search Results: ~5,690,000
Possible Domains: gamehubapp.de</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tkashkin/GameHub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameHub</a> is a popular game library manager</li>
<li>it also sounds like a popular adult site 😁</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="whats-next">What's Next?<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#whats-next" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What's Next?" title="Direct link to What's Next?">​</a></h2>
<p>We understand your eagerness for a new name, and we are equally committed to distancing ourselves from the old one. Taking into account all the suggested names and feedback, we engaged in extensive internal brainstorming, free from outside influences.</p>
<p>We sought a name that is descriptive, intuitive, and effectively conveys the purpose of our app. Additionally, we aimed for a name that is easily memorable and emphasizes the ownership and control of a self-hosted server, security, and exclusivity.</p>
<p>Introducing our new name: <strong>GameVault</strong><br>
<!-- -->Available soon under this domain: <a href="https://gamevau.lt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gamevau.lt</a></p>
<p>We have already secured the domain and registered the name wherever possible. The transition process will commence shortly. We are eager to hear your thoughts on the new name. Do you like it?</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_hwRS" id="special-thanks-️">Special Thanks ❤️<a href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/#special-thanks-%EF%B8%8F" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Special Thanks ❤️" title="Direct link to Special Thanks ❤️">​</a></h2>
<p>Well, as you all know, this was quite a journey to get here, and we wanted to give our special thanks to:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Everybody who gave this project's idea a chance, even if the name was kind of weird.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everybody who made suggestions on our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> server and participated in the discussions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everybody who voted.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A special shoutout to @KairuByte on <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> for coming up with the name GameVault.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We would also like to extend our gratitude to <a href="https://selfhosted.show/101?t=2731" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Selfhosted Podcast</a> for discussing our app. (Brent, we are excited to hear your thoughts on the new name from a marketing standpoint 😜)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Last but not least, thank you to <a href="https://selfh.st/newsletter/2023-07-07/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Self-Hosted Newsletter</a> for mentioning our release.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Thank you all for your continued support!</p>
<p>We will keep you updated as the transition unfolds. In the meantime, head over to our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> channel to celebrate and share your thoughts on the new name.</p>
<p>Stay tuned!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="poll results" term="poll results"/>
        <category label="renaming app" term="renaming app"/>
        <category label="community feedback" term="community feedback"/>
        <category label="GameStash" term="GameStash"/>
        <category label="GameVault" term="GameVault"/>
        <category label="GameShelf" term="GameShelf"/>
        <category label="Harbor" term="Harbor"/>
        <category label="GameHub" term="GameHub"/>
        <category label="market analysis" term="market analysis"/>
        <category label="new name announcement" term="new name announcement"/>
        <category label="GameVault domain" term="GameVault domain"/>
        <category label="special thanks" term="special thanks"/>
        <category label="Selfhosted Podcast" term="Selfhosted Podcast"/>
        <category label="Self-Hosted Newsletter" term="Self-Hosted Newsletter"/>
        <category label="transition process" term="transition process"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Closer Look at GameVaults 'Source-Available' Nature]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/13/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/13/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p>
<p>today i want to clarify why GameVault isn't considered "open-source" by definition.</p>
<p>You see, GameVault is what we like to call <a href="https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Source-available_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"source-available"</a> software. This means that our code is open for you to explore and modify, but it doesn't fully meet all the criteria of being considered open-source. I want to take a moment to explain what open-source truly means and why we've taken a slightly different approach.</p>
<p>According to the widely recognized definitions, <a href="https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"open-source"</a> software, as one would think, not only provides access to the source code but also offers certain freedoms to its users. It allows them to use, modify, and distribute the software freely, even for commercial purposes.</p>
<p>For a self-hosted app like GameVault, we believe it's crucual to disclose the source code. We want you, our users, to have full transparency and control over the software you use on your servers. We don't want you to be unaware of what's happening behind the scenes, as is sometimes the case with closed-source applications like Plex, for example.</p>
<p>Now, you may be wondering why we didn't make GameVault fully open-source. The answer lies in our desire to protect our code from unauthorized use and commercial exploitation. While we absolutely encourage you to copy, modify, and share our code for personal use, we want to prevent others from profiting off our hard work by selling our software without our consent.</p>
<p>It's important to acknowledge that maintaining and developing a software project requires resources. While we admire the open-source community and its valuable contributions, sustaining GameVault solely through donations or offering it for free indefinitely is not feasible. For instance, Jellyfin, a popular open-source app developed over a decade, generates only around $13,500 per year (according to their opencollective page). In contrast, Plex, a closed-source alternative, earns a significant $8.5 million annually. Our company's main goal is to keep the core functionality of GameVault free, but we also need to explore ways to generate revenue in order to support its future growth and improvement. We are currently considering monetizing additional convenience features for the Client Application in the future, although nothing has been finalized yet.</p>
<p>We genuinely appreciate your understanding. As a small business with just two members, we strive to provide you with a valuable product but cannot continue to do so as volunteers indefinitely. Sustaining losses in the long term would not be sustainable, especially considering our local tax obligations. We have families and commitments that cannot be neglected, and this project is not our primary job. Therefore, please understand that GameVault may not strictly align with the traditional definition of "open-source," and we no longer characterize it as such. Our intention is to be transparent and present our perspective. Your understanding, support, and empathy mean a great deal to us.</p>
<p>If you have any thoughts or comments on this topic, we'd be more than happy to hear from you. Feel free to share your feedback on our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> server. We truly value your input and look forward to engaging with you there.</p>
<p><code>EDIT: Updated Application Name</code></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="source-available software" term="source-available software"/>
        <category label="open-source" term="open-source"/>
        <category label="transparency" term="transparency"/>
        <category label="control" term="control"/>
        <category label="software development" term="software development"/>
        <category label="code access" term="code access"/>
        <category label="hybrid model" term="hybrid model"/>
        <category label="software licensing" term="software licensing"/>
        <category label="revenue generation" term="revenue generation"/>
        <category label="user engagement" term="user engagement"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battling Harassment and Trolls in Our App Community]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/09/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/09/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey folks,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey folks,</p>
<p>We have an important update to share with you all while our poll is in progress. It has come to our attention that a group of individuals has been engaging in harassing, blackmailing, and threatening behavior towards us.</p>
<p>It began with spam on our Issue Trackers and <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> Server but this situation has escalated to the point where these individuals went so far as to search me up on LinkedIn and threaten to inform my employer with baseless accusations of racism because of trivial reasons like the branch name in our github project being "master". Moreover, we have received reports that these trolls have extended their actions directly to other members of this server, attempting to spread negative narratives and disrupting the community atmosphere.</p>
<p>To address this issue, we kindly request that you promptly report any encounters with these trolls to both <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a> and our dedicated team of moderators. By doing so, we can take appropriate measures to handle the situation and maintain a safe environment for all.</p>
<p>We would like to emphasize that we are not racist individuals, but rather developers who decided to share our hard work with the community, hoping to bring joy and utility to everyone. Unfortunately, we did not anticipate encountering such creepy behavior when we made the project public. It has made us question whether it was the right decision to open up our work in the first place.</p>
<p>If you appreciate our efforts and would like to support us and the app, we humbly ask for your financial assistance. Even a small contribution of five bucks on <a href="https://ko-fi.com/phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kofi</a> would go a long way in helping us maintain our motivation and dedication. Alternatively, if monetary support isn't possible, we would be incredibly grateful if you could share kind words about how the GameVault app has positively impacted your life in the #chat channel. Your encouragement means the world to us. 🥰</p>
<p>In addition, we encourage you to continue reporting any bugs you encounter and submitting feature requests in the respective GitHub trackers. With your valuable input, we can continue improving the app and making it even better.</p>
<p>Remember, the success of this project relies on your support and engagement. Let's stand together against these trolls and ensure a positive and inclusive community experience. Thank you for your attention and understanding.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="harassment" term="harassment"/>
        <category label="blackmail" term="blackmail"/>
        <category label="threats" term="threats"/>
        <category label="spam" term="spam"/>
        <category label="trolls" term="trolls"/>
        <category label="negative narratives" term="negative narratives"/>
        <category label="safe environment" term="safe environment"/>
        <category label="racist" term="racist"/>
        <category label="developers" term="developers"/>
        <category label="public" term="public"/>
        <category label="creepy behavior" term="creepy behavior"/>
        <category label="app" term="app"/>
        <category label="support" term="support"/>
        <category label="financial assistance" term="financial assistance"/>
        <category label="motivation" term="motivation"/>
        <category label="GameVault app" term="GameVault app"/>
        <category label="bugs" term="bugs"/>
        <category label="feature requests" term="feature requests"/>
        <category label="improvement" term="improvement"/>
        <category label="success" term="success"/>
        <category label="engagement" term="engagement"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing a New, Family-Friendly Name for this project!]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/08/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/08/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, everyone!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, everyone!</p>
<p>We have an important announcement to share about our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Source-available_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">source-available</a> gaming platform, project. We have listened to your feedback and concerns, and now we need your help in choosing a new, family-friendly name that better reflects our platform's values. To make this decision-making process more convenient, we have created a poll with 100 potential names, suggested by you on our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a>, some of which were generated by AI. Your participation in shaping the future of our platform is greatly appreciated.</p>
<p>We kindly request your support in selecting a new name for our gaming platform. The poll offers a variety of names, and we ask that you choose at least 10 names (10%) that appeal to you. By gathering diverse input and minimizing bias, we aim to create an inclusive and enjoyable experience for all users. We apologize if the current name has caused any discomfort, and we are committed to creating a welcoming environment for gamers.</p>
<p>To cast your votes and contribute to the selection of a new, family-friendly name for our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Source-available_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">source-available</a> gaming platform, please click on the link provided at the end of this post. Your voice matters, and together, we can find a name that truly represents our app's essence. The results will be announced on this blog around July 15, 2023.</p>
<p>We sincerely appreciate your support and encourage you to stay tuned for updates as we continue to improve our platform based on your valuable feedback.</p>
<p>Link to the poll: <a href="https://forms.gle/cYsURG6BqMXcxE3B8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://forms.gle/cYsURG6BqMXcxE3B8</a></p>
<p>Happy voting!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="source-available" term="source-available"/>
        <category label="gaming platform" term="gaming platform"/>
        <category label="GameVault" term="GameVault"/>
        <category label="new name" term="new name"/>
        <category label="family-friendly" term="family-friendly"/>
        <category label="poll" term="poll"/>
        <category label="AI-generated names" term="AI-generated names"/>
        <category label="feedback" term="feedback"/>
        <category label="inclusivity" term="inclusivity"/>
        <category label="user participation" term="user participation"/>
        <category label="announcement" term="announcement"/>
        <category label="decision-making" term="decision-making"/>
        <category label="community" term="community"/>
        <category label="platform values" term="platform values"/>
        <category label="voting" term="voting"/>
        <category label="future development" term="future development"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing GameVault 🚀 - The self-hosted gaming platform for DRM-free games]]></title>
        <id>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/01/</id>
        <link href="https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/01/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Guys,]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Guys,</p>
<p>Our team has been working tirelessly for the past year on creating GameVault, the source-available, self-hosted, and free alternative to traditional cloud-based game platforms like Steam, Origin, Epic Games, and GoG. We are excited to share that GameVault is now available for everyone to use, and we are delighted to disclose it to the community.</p>
<p>With GameVault, you can play and track games together with your friends on a shared file server, free from any restrictions that traditional game platforms may impose. We have designed it to work with DRM-free games, providing a unique solution for those who want a more flexible and open approach to gaming. Think of it like Jellyfin, but for Videogames.</p>
<p>GameVault offers a self-hosted approach that gives you complete control over your gaming experience. The platform enables you to browse your server's game collection, securely download games, launch and play them, and even track your playtimes and progress - regardless of whether the server is offline. Additionally, you can compare stats and play states with other users on the server.</p>
<p>Our server features offer automatic indexing of games on the file system into a database, enrichment of games with metadata like tags and genres using RAWG API, multi-user authentication, and configurable logging. We have also implemented health monitoring, full-text search, filters, sorting, pagination, and a fully documented API. The GameVault platform is highly configurable to suit your needs.</p>
<p>We are thrilled that you have found us, and we invite you to try GameVault today. We would be grateful for any contributions, feedback, bug reports, and feature requests you might have. You can also support us by donating using the links provided on our website. If you have any questions or would like to connect with other GameVault users, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord</a>, Reddit and Lemmy communities - links to which are available in the footer.</p>
<p>We are passionate about creating a gaming experience that is more open, flexible, and enjoyable for everyone. We hope you will join us on this journey and experience the benefits of a truly source-available alternative to traditional game platforms with GameVault.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Alper Alkan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/Alfagun74</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="gaming" term="gaming"/>
        <category label="GameVault" term="GameVault"/>
        <category label="source-available" term="source-available"/>
        <category label="self-hosted" term="self-hosted"/>
        <category label="alternative" term="alternative"/>
        <category label="cloud-based game platforms" term="cloud-based game platforms"/>
        <category label="DRM-free games" term="DRM-free games"/>
        <category label="file server" term="file server"/>
        <category label="multi-user authentication" term="multi-user authentication"/>
        <category label="metadata" term="metadata"/>
        <category label="RAWG API" term="RAWG API"/>
        <category label="health monitoring" term="health monitoring"/>
        <category label="API" term="API"/>
        <category label="Discord server" term="Discord server"/>
        <category label="Reddit forum" term="Reddit forum"/>
        <category label="Lemmy forum" term="Lemmy forum"/>
    </entry>
</feed>