<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>GameVault Blog</title>
        <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog</link>
        <description>GameVault Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Please help us prioritize!]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/29/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/29/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hello everyone!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone!</p><p>We hope you're all doing well. We wanted to take a moment to express our heartfelt gratitude for the flood of feature requests and bug reports that have been pouring into our issue trackers. Your enthusiasm and dedication to making GameVault even better are truly inspiring to us.</p><p>As many of you may already know, GameVault is a passion project for us, and while we are mostly convinced by your fantastic ideas, it may take some time for us to implement them. Our team meetings happen in our free time, and although we genuinely want to incorporate your suggestions into our roadmap, we are limited by the time and capacity we can dedicate to the project. Moreover, we want to ensure that the features we develop are refined, polished, and also the most desired in the users' opinions, which adds to the timeline.</p><p>We believe that collaboration with our incredible community is the key to success, and that's why we want to introduce you to our Roadmap. It displays all new issues, planned tasks we want to work on, and all the ongoing work in a well-organized Kanban Board. <a href="https://github.com/orgs/Phalcode/projects/4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You can find it right here.</a></p><p>To ensure that GameVault's development aligns better with your needs, we kindly request your active participation. By voting on GitHub with a Thumbs Up or a Thumbs Down on new and planned issues, you can help us prioritize them effectively. We value your opinion: What features do you feel are most crucial? What aspects of the platform do you find most bothersome? What issues do you see as unnecessary or bloated? Your input will mainly shape the direction we take.</p><p>If you're eager to go the extra mile and actively contribute to shaping GameVault further, we invite you to <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">join our Discord community</a> and becoming a "Council Member". By becoming a "Council Member" and enabling Poll Notifications under "#Channels &amp; Roles", you will have a direct say in the future of GameVault because you will get notifications about opinion polls we run from time to time.</p><p>We cannot stress enough how much we appreciate your involvement in our endeavor to create the ultimate gaming experience for all of you. Your passion and feedback are invaluable, and we are committed to making GameVault the best it can be, together.</p><p>Thank you for being part of this amazing journey with us!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>community</category>
            <category>GameVault</category>
            <category>development</category>
            <category>roadmap</category>
            <category>collaboration</category>
            <category>feedback</category>
            <category>GitHub</category>
            <category>voting</category>
            <category>features</category>
            <category>platform</category>
            <category>Kanban Board</category>
            <category>Discord</category>
            <category>Council Member</category>
            <category>polls</category>
            <category>gaming experience</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Celebrating 600+ Installations and announcing the upcoming big feature]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/24/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey everyone,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p><p>We're excited to share some great news with you all! GameVault has reached a small milestone with over 600 official installations of our GameVault Client Application. What's even more amazing is that around 200 dedicated users, a third of these installations, have joined our Discord community to connect, chat, and share their experiences.</p><p>We want to express our immense gratitude for your incredible support, feedback, and love for GameVault. Your ongoing encouragement inspires us to push boundaries and enhance your gaming experience. We're thrilled to announce that an awesome update is being worked on right now - the highly anticipated release of GameVault's Installation Pipeline!</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="gamevaults-installation-pipeline">GameVault's Installation Pipeline<a href="#gamevaults-installation-pipeline" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to GameVault's Installation Pipeline" title="Direct link to GameVault's Installation Pipeline">​</a></h4><p>The Installation Pipeline is designed to revolutionize how you install and manage your games. It was suggested by members on our discord server. We understand the challenges of navigating through different installation processes, especially for family members who may not be tech-savvy. With the Installation Pipeline, our goal is to simplify the entire process and make it user-friendly. Whether you're an experienced gamer or not, this update will make installing games easier for you.</p><p>You can read the details <a href="https://github.com/Phalcode/gamevault-app/issues/18" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here on the GitHub issue</a>.</p><p>Stay tuned for its upcoming release, and to be among the first to try out this awesome feature, make sure to subscribe to the <code>@Updates</code> Role on our Discord server, if you haven't already. We'll ping you as soon as it's live!</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="join-us-on-lemmy">Join us on Lemmy<a href="#join-us-on-lemmy" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Join us on Lemmy" title="Direct link to Join us on Lemmy">​</a></h4><p>To further connect with our amazing community, we're excited to announce the launch of our <a href="https://lemmy.world/c/phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">official Lemmy community</a>. From now on, we'll also regularly share new blog posts there, providing you with more ways to stay informed and engaged. Join the Lemmy forum and become part of the growing GameVault community!</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="share-gamevault-with-others">Share GameVault with Others<a href="#share-gamevault-with-others" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Share GameVault with Others" title="Direct link to Share GameVault with Others">​</a></h4><p>As we celebrate this milestone and eagerly anticipate more exciting updates, we invite you to spread the word about GameVault among your friends, family, and gaming or self-hosting communities. Your personal recommendations and referrals have played a significant role in our journey so far, and we believe they'll continue to do so in the future.</p><p>We want to express our heartfelt appreciation for the feature requests, discussions, and invaluable help on our GitHub. Your support and collaborative efforts help a lot.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="support-us">Support Us<a href="#support-us" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Support Us" title="Direct link to Support Us">​</a></h4><p>As we move forward, we kindly ask for your continued support. GameVault's success is currently solely built upon our incredible community, and your encouragement is what fuels us. If you love our app and believe in our vision, please consider supporting us in any way you can. It could even be something simple like a rating on the Microsoft Store. Your backing empowers us to keep our hard work going.</p><p>We're eagerly looking forward to celebrating more achievements with all of you.</p><p>Stay tuned, stay connected, and let's continue this journey together!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>GameVault milestone</category>
            <category>official installations</category>
            <category>Discord community growth</category>
            <category>gratitude</category>
            <category>feedback</category>
            <category>love for GameVault</category>
            <category>upcoming update</category>
            <category>Installation Pipeline</category>
            <category>simplifying game installation</category>
            <category>GitHub issue</category>
            <category>subscription to Updates role</category>
            <category>Lemmy community launch</category>
            <category>sharing blog posts</category>
            <category>spreading the word</category>
            <category>support request</category>
            <category>continued support</category>
            <category>celebration of achievements</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Migrations are finally completed]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/20/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey folks,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey folks,</p><p>Great news. We've successfully migrated our App name in its entirety and will resume advertising as soon as it's published on the Microsoft Store.</p><p>Just a heads up, there might be a surge of new users joining the Discord server due to us promoting Gamevault across all available platforms now.</p><p>You're welcome to join in and spread the word about GameVault with your friends, family, social network, or colleagues!</p><p><strong>Let's decipher the mystery behind the new logo:</strong>
<img loading="lazy" alt="logo" src="/assets/images/logo-text-and-image-sbs-6a7a4b169bd1cf62f643469e715ae759.png" width="1000" height="103" class="img_OS_2"></p><ul><li>The Box represents a Vault with a Keyhole, but it also symbolizes a game dice.</li><li>The Keyhole represents a Keyhole, and simultaneously signifies a game piece.</li></ul><p>Did you find the logo concept creative? Share your thoughts on <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">discord</a>!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>app name migration</category>
            <category>Microsoft Store publication</category>
            <category>surge of new users</category>
            <category>Discord server promotion</category>
            <category>spreading the word</category>
            <category>logo deciphering</category>
            <category>box representation</category>
            <category>keyhole representation</category>
            <category>logo concept discussion</category>
            <category>Discord channel</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quick Migration Update and new Logo]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/19/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/19/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey guys,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys,</p><p>We have a brief update on the progress of the name migration.</p><p>We've successfully completed the migration of the backend application, which is now accessible as <code>gamevault-backend</code> instead of <code>crackpipe-backend</code>.</p><p>Furthermore, we've migrated the documentation and acquired this domain gamevau.lt. We've set up redirects for our previous domain and the demo server as well.</p><p>Lastly we migrated our Subreddit from r/Crackpipe to <a href="https://reddit.com/r/Phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">r/Phalcode</a> and opened up a new community on <a href="https://lemmy.world/c/phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lemmy</a>. All further Updates and discussions regarding GameVault can be found there.</p><p>We're nearly finished, you might say.</p><p>The only remaining task is the Client Application. We're actively working on it and currently testing the application on our developer edition. Soon, you'll be able to seamlessly update your client with the new name and appearance.</p><p>In the meantime, our graphic designer has crafted a fresh logo for our new name, GameVault.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="logo" src="/assets/images/logo-text-and-image-sbs-6a7a4b169bd1cf62f643469e715ae759.png" width="1000" height="103" class="img_OS_2"></p><p>To make good use of your time while the migrations are in progress, what do you speculate the new logo represents?</p><p>Share your theories in gamevaults #chat channel on <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">discord</a>! We'll reveal the answer and shoutout the winner(s) in the next blog post, once the migration is finalized!</p><p>Until then ✌️</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>name migration progress</category>
            <category>backend application migration</category>
            <category>documentation migration</category>
            <category>domain acquisition</category>
            <category>Subreddit migration</category>
            <category>Lemmy community</category>
            <category>Client Application update</category>
            <category>testing</category>
            <category>new logo</category>
            <category>speculation</category>
            <category>Discord channel</category>
            <category>migration finalization</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Name]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/15/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey everyone,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p><p>We are thrilled to announce that the poll for choosing a new name for our app is finally over. The process of transitioning to the new name will commence very soon, and we can't wait to share the exciting updates with you.</p><p>But first, let's dive into the poll results and shed some light on the important facts without further delay:</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="summary">Summary<a href="#summary" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Summary" title="Direct link to Summary">​</a></h2><p>In total, 71 people participated in the poll, providing us with valuable data to draw conclusions from. Here's a summary of the key findings:</p><ul><li><p>52.1% of the community voted against using any terms related to piracy in the app. We understand and respect this choice because it would harm our business and attract the wrong users, as we have no affiliation with piracy.</p></li><li><p>42.3% of the community voted to recommend the app under a different name but not with its current name. This feedback motivated us to rename the app, confirming that it wasn't just a few critics on Reddit. We want to expand our community to include the families, friends, and colleagues of these people. So please, help us spread the word about the name change!</p></li><li><p>36.6% of you said you wouldn't contribute to our app at all solely because of its name, even if you had the opportunity. We depend on these contributions to grow and improve, so we now encourage you to participate!</p></li></ul><p>Without further ado, here are the top 5 names that emerged as winners in the poll:</p><ol><li>GameStash (38%)</li><li>GameVault (35.2%)</li><li>GameShelf (31%)</li><li>Harbor (29.6%)</li><li>GameHub (28.2%)</li></ol><p>As mentioned earlier, we conducted the poll without conducting market analysis beforehand. However, we recognized the significance of making an informed decision for the benefit of the community. Consequently, we proceeded to analyze each name after the poll to ensure the chosen name resonates with our vision.</p><p>Allow us to share the summarized results of our market analysis:</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="market-analysis">Market Analysis<a href="#market-analysis" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Market Analysis" title="Direct link to Market Analysis">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="1-gamestash">1. GameStash<a href="#1-gamestash" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 1. GameStash" title="Direct link to 1. GameStash">​</a></h3><p>Google Search Results: ~33,600<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: gamestash.de</p><ul><li>There's already an app called <a href="https://gamestash.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameStash</a> that offers similar features to ours.</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="2-gamevault">2. GameVault<a href="#2-gamevault" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 2. GameVault" title="Direct link to 2. GameVault">​</a></h3><p>Google Search Results: ~800,000<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: gamevau.lt, game-vault.de</p><ul><li>The term "GameVault" is associated with a popular online casino/gambling application called <a href="https://gamevault999.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameVault999</a>.</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="3-gameshelf">3. GameShelf<a href="#3-gameshelf" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 3. GameShelf" title="Direct link to 3. GameShelf">​</a></h3><p>Google Search Results: ~560,000<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: gameshelf.de</p><ul><li>The name "Gameshelf" is already used by two existing applications. One is a <a href="https://gameshelf.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Board-Game-Collection Viewer</a>, and the other is a <a href="https://gameshelf.dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gaming Backlog</a> app.</li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="4-harbor">4. Harbor<a href="#4-harbor" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 4. Harbor" title="Direct link to 4. Harbor">​</a></h3><p>Google Search Results: ~393,000,000<br>
<!-- -->Possible Domains: harborapp.de</p><ul><li><p>"Harbor" is a very common word, making it challenging to find a suitable domain that aligns with our brand identity.</p></li><li><p>Additionally, there's a well-known app called <a href="https://goharbor.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Harbor on the Market</a> related to Docker/Kubernetes.</p></li></ul><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="5-gamehub">5. GameHub<a href="#5-gamehub" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 5. GameHub" title="Direct link to 5. GameHub">​</a></h3><p>Google Search Results: ~5,690,000
Possible Domains: gamehubapp.de</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/tkashkin/GameHub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GameHub</a> is a popular game library manager</li><li>it also sounds like a popular adult site 😁</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="whats-next">What's Next?<a href="#whats-next" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What's Next?" title="Direct link to What's Next?">​</a></h2><p>We understand your eagerness for a new name, and we are equally committed to distancing ourselves from the old one. Taking into account all the suggested names and feedback, we engaged in extensive internal brainstorming, free from outside influences.</p><p>We sought a name that is descriptive, intuitive, and effectively conveys the purpose of our app. Additionally, we aimed for a name that is easily memorable and emphasizes the ownership and control of a self-hosted server, security, and exclusivity.</p><p>Introducing our new name: <strong>GameVault</strong><br>
<!-- -->Available soon under this domain: <a href="https://gamevau.lt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gamevau.lt</a></p><p>We have already secured the domain and registered the name wherever possible. The transition process will commence shortly. We are eager to hear your thoughts on the new name. Do you like it?</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="special-thanks-️">Special Thanks ❤️<a href="#special-thanks-️" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Special Thanks ❤️" title="Direct link to Special Thanks ❤️">​</a></h2><p>Well, as you all know, this was quite a journey to get here, and we wanted to give our special thanks to:</p><ul><li><p>Everybody who gave this project's idea a chance, even if the name was kind of weird.</p></li><li><p>Everybody who made suggestions on our Discord server and participated in the discussions.</p></li><li><p>Everybody who voted.</p></li><li><p>A special shoutout to @KairuByte on Discord for coming up with the name GameVault.</p></li><li><p>We would also like to extend our gratitude to <a href="https://selfhosted.show/101?t=2731" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Selfhosted Podcast</a> for discussing our app. (Brent, we are excited to hear your thoughts on the new name from a marketing standpoint 😜)</p></li><li><p>Last but not least, thank you to <a href="https://selfh.st/newsletter/2023-07-07/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Self-Hosted Newsletter</a> for mentioning our release.</p></li></ul><p>Thank you all for your continued support!</p><p>We will keep you updated as the transition unfolds. In the meantime, head over to our Discord channel to celebrate and share your thoughts on the new name.</p><p>Oh, and by the way, just a heads up: The transition for the "crackpipe_user" field in the database might take a bit longer, because it will need a migration. It seems getting 500 users "off the crackpipe" isn't as easy as we thought! 😉</p><p>Stay tuned!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>poll results</category>
            <category>renaming app</category>
            <category>community feedback</category>
            <category>GameStash</category>
            <category>GameVault</category>
            <category>GameShelf</category>
            <category>Harbor</category>
            <category>GameHub</category>
            <category>market analysis</category>
            <category>new name announcement</category>
            <category>GameVault domain</category>
            <category>special thanks</category>
            <category>Selfhosted Podcast</category>
            <category>Self-Hosted Newsletter</category>
            <category>transition process</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Closer Look at Crackpipes 'Source-Available' Nature]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/13/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/13/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey everyone,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p><p>today i want to clarify why Crackpipe isn't considered "open-source" by definition.</p><p>You see, Crackpipe is what we like to call <a href="https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Source-available_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"source-available"</a> software. This means that our code is open for you to explore and modify, but it doesn't fully meet all the criteria of being considered open-source. I want to take a moment to explain what open-source truly means and why we've taken a slightly different approach.</p><p>According to the widely recognized definitions, <a href="https://wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">"open-source"</a> software, as one would think, not only provides access to the source code but also offers certain freedoms to its users. It allows them to use, modify, and distribute the software freely, even for commercial purposes.</p><p>For a self-hosted app like Crackpipe, we believe it's crucual to disclose the source code. We want you, our users, to have full transparency and control over the software you use on your servers. We don't want you to be unaware of what's happening behind the scenes, as is sometimes the case with closed-source applications like Plex, for example.</p><p>Now, you may be wondering why we didn't make Crackpipe fully open-source. The answer lies in our desire to protect our code from unauthorized use and commercial exploitation. While we absolutely encourage you to copy, modify, and share our code for personal use, we want to prevent others from profiting off our hard work by selling our software without our consent.</p><p>It's important to acknowledge that maintaining and developing a software project requires resources. While we admire the open-source community and its valuable contributions, sustaining Crackpipe solely through donations or offering it for free indefinitely is not feasible. For instance, Jellyfin, a popular open-source app developed over a decade, generates only around $13,500 per year (according to their opencollective page). In contrast, Plex, a closed-source alternative, earns a significant $8.5 million annually. Our company's main goal is to keep the core functionality of Crackpipe free, but we also need to explore ways to generate revenue in order to support its future growth and improvement. We are currently considering monetizing additional convenience features for the Client Application in the future, although nothing has been finalized yet.</p><p>We genuinely appreciate your understanding. As a small business with just two members, we strive to provide you with a valuable product but cannot continue to do so as volunteers indefinitely. Sustaining losses in the long term would not be sustainable, especially considering our local tax obligations. We have families and commitments that cannot be neglected, and this project is not our primary job. Therefore, please understand that Crackpipe may not strictly align with the traditional definition of "open-source," and we no longer characterize it as such. Our intention is to be transparent and present our perspective. Your understanding, support, and empathy mean a great deal to us.</p><p>If you have any thoughts or comments on this topic, we'd be more than happy to hear from you. Feel free to share your feedback on our Discord server. We truly value your input and look forward to engaging with you there.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>source-available software</category>
            <category>open-source</category>
            <category>transparency</category>
            <category>control</category>
            <category>software development</category>
            <category>code access</category>
            <category>hybrid model</category>
            <category>software licensing</category>
            <category>revenue generation</category>
            <category>user engagement</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battling Harassment and Trolls in Our App Community]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/09/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/09/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey folks,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey folks,</p><p>We have an important update to share with you all while our poll is in progress. It has come to our attention that a group of individuals has been engaging in harassing, blackmailing, and threatening behavior towards us.</p><p>It began with spam on our Issue Trackers and Discord Server but this situation has escalated to the point where these individuals went so far as to search me up on LinkedIn and threaten to inform my employer with baseless accusations of racism because of trivial reasons like the branch name in our github project being "master". Moreover, we have received reports that these trolls have extended their actions directly to other members of this server, attempting to spread negative narratives and disrupting the community atmosphere.</p><p>To address this issue, we kindly request that you promptly report any encounters with these trolls to both Discord and our dedicated team of moderators. By doing so, we can take appropriate measures to handle the situation and maintain a safe environment for all.</p><p>We would like to emphasize that we are not racist individuals, but rather developers who decided to share our hard work with the community, hoping to bring joy and utility to everyone. Unfortunately, we did not anticipate encountering such creepy behavior when we made the project public. It has made us question whether it was the right decision to open up our work in the first place.</p><p>If you appreciate our efforts and would like to support us and the app, we humbly ask for your financial assistance. Even a small contribution of $5 on <a href="https://ko-fi.com/phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kofi</a> would go a long way in helping us maintain our motivation and dedication. Alternatively, if monetary support isn't possible, we would be incredibly grateful if you could share kind words about how the Crackpipe app has positively impacted your life in the #chat channel. Your encouragement means the world to us. 🥰</p><p>In addition, we encourage you to continue reporting any bugs you encounter and submitting feature requests in the respective GitHub trackers. With your valuable input, we can continue improving the app and making it even better.</p><p>Remember, the success of this project relies on your support and engagement. Let's stand together against these trolls and ensure a positive and inclusive community experience. Thank you for your attention and understanding.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>harassment</category>
            <category>blackmail</category>
            <category>threats</category>
            <category>spam</category>
            <category>trolls</category>
            <category>negative narratives</category>
            <category>safe environment</category>
            <category>racist</category>
            <category>developers</category>
            <category>public</category>
            <category>creepy behavior</category>
            <category>app</category>
            <category>support</category>
            <category>financial assistance</category>
            <category>motivation</category>
            <category>Crackpipe app</category>
            <category>bugs</category>
            <category>feature requests</category>
            <category>improvement</category>
            <category>success</category>
            <category>engagement</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Choosing a New, Family-Friendly Name for Crackpipe!]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/08/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hello, everyone!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, everyone!</p><p>We have an important announcement to share about our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Source-available_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">source-available</a> gaming platform, Crackpipe. We have listened to your feedback and concerns, and now we need your help in choosing a new, family-friendly name that better reflects our platform's values. To make this decision-making process more convenient, we have created a poll with 100 potential names, suggested by you on our discord, some of which were generated by AI. Your participation in shaping the future of our platform is greatly appreciated.</p><p>We kindly request your support in selecting a new name for our gaming platform. The poll offers a variety of names, and we ask that you choose at least 10 names (10%) that appeal to you. By gathering diverse input and minimizing bias, we aim to create an inclusive and enjoyable experience for all users. We apologize if the current name has caused any discomfort, and we are committed to creating a welcoming environment for gamers.</p><p>To cast your votes and contribute to the selection of a new, family-friendly name for our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Source-available_software" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">source-available</a> gaming platform, please click on the link provided at the end of this post. Your voice matters, and together, we can find a name that truly represents our app's essence. The results will be announced on this blog around July 15, 2023.</p><p>We sincerely appreciate your support and encourage you to stay tuned for updates as we continue to improve our platform based on your valuable feedback.</p><p>Link to the poll: <a href="https://forms.gle/cYsURG6BqMXcxE3B8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://forms.gle/cYsURG6BqMXcxE3B8</a></p><p>Happy voting!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>source-available</category>
            <category>gaming platform</category>
            <category>Crackpipe</category>
            <category>new name</category>
            <category>family-friendly</category>
            <category>poll</category>
            <category>AI-generated names</category>
            <category>feedback</category>
            <category>inclusivity</category>
            <category>user participation</category>
            <category>announcement</category>
            <category>decision-making</category>
            <category>community</category>
            <category>platform values</category>
            <category>voting</category>
            <category>future development</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Bumpy Start - Addressing Feedback and Looking Forward]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/03/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/03/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey everyone,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone,</p><p>What an eventful day it has been! We recently launched our app and shared it on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/14pdu0m/introducing_crackpipe_your_decentralized" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this Reddit post</a>, and it has sparked some controversies. We want to take this opportunity to address the feedback and allegations in an official statement.</p><p>So let's go through the controversies:</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="regarding-the-name-crackpipe">Regarding the name Crackpipe<a href="#regarding-the-name-crackpipe" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Regarding the name Crackpipe" title="Direct link to Regarding the name Crackpipe">​</a></h4><p>We want to clarify that the name "Crackpipe" was initially meant as an inside joke between me and my friend, intended for a tool used by a limited audience. We just got used to it and went on, when deciding to release it to the public. We understand that some find the name inappropriate or uncomfortable, and we sincerely apologize for any distress caused. We are open to renaming the entire application to ensure it aligns better with our community's values. Your input is essential to us, so please <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">join our Discord server</a> and share your creative suggestions for a new name in the #new-name channel. Soon, we'll have a public poll on our blog where you can vote for your favorite name or the existing one.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="clarification-on-the-term-liberal">Clarification on the term "liberal"<a href="#clarification-on-the-term-liberal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Clarification on the term &quot;liberal&quot;" title="Direct link to Clarification on the term &quot;liberal&quot;">​</a></h4><p>As non-native English speakers, we made an oversight in using the term "liberal," which we intended to mean "free" or "libre." We have already rectified this mistake.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="the-use-of-pepe-the-frog-as-a-profile-picture">The use of Pepe the Frog as a profile picture<a href="#the-use-of-pepe-the-frog-as-a-profile-picture" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The use of Pepe the Frog as a profile picture" title="Direct link to The use of Pepe the Frog as a profile picture">​</a></h4><p>We apologize for not being aware of the misuse of the Pepe the Frog meme as a symbol of Nazis and white supremacism. That misuse is not a thing in europe. Originally, we only knew the frog as a twitch emote/meme and used it without any harmful intentions. In response to your feedback, we have changed the profile picture to a cute penguin.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="addressing-concerns-about-piracy">Addressing concerns about piracy<a href="#addressing-concerns-about-piracy" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Addressing concerns about piracy" title="Direct link to Addressing concerns about piracy">​</a></h4><p>We'd like to emphasize that our app isn't intended for unlawful activities, which include piracy. When we refer to DRM-free games, we still imply games that are acquired legally. This encompasses legitimate sources like archive.org, GOG, or the Humble Trove. Our goal is to consolidate your games in one location, given that they are part of the RAWG Database.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="regarding-the-origins-of-the-application">Regarding the origins of the application<a href="#regarding-the-origins-of-the-application" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Regarding the origins of the application" title="Direct link to Regarding the origins of the application">​</a></h4><p>We assure you that this application was entirely developed by us, and any similarity to other projects is purely coincidental. We cleaned up our repositories to remove meaningless commits before going public, which may have caused confusion.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="on-the-marketing-strategy">On the marketing strategy<a href="#on-the-marketing-strategy" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to On the marketing strategy" title="Direct link to On the marketing strategy">​</a></h4><p>We want to clarify that the controversy surrounding the app was not a planned marketing stunt. As programmers that developed this in spare time, we simply did not anticipate such a strong reaction to a free app.</p><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_TVGU" id="transparancy-regarding-financial-and-future-plans">Transparancy regarding financial and future plans<a href="#transparancy-regarding-financial-and-future-plans" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Transparancy regarding financial and future plans" title="Direct link to Transparancy regarding financial and future plans">​</a></h4><p>Currently, we rely on your <a href="https://ko-fi.com/phalcode" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">financial support through Kofi</a>. Building an active and engaged user base is our primary focus before considering the addition of any paid features in the future. So for now just enjoy the functionalities.</p><hr><p>In conclusion, we appreciate all the feedback and kind words we have received. If you believe in the app's concept but are concerned about the current name, please feel free to suggest a new one and participate in the voting process on our <a href="https://discord.gg/NEdNen2dSu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Discord server</a>.</p><p>We are determined to improve and grow, and despite the bumpy start, we hope you'll enjoy the app and its functionality. We look forward to fostering a vibrant and supportive community around it.</p><p>For further updates, you can follow our blog. And new posts will also be shared on our Reddit, Lemmy and Discord server.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>gaming</category>
            <category>Crackpipe</category>
            <category>app launch</category>
            <category>controversy</category>
            <category>official statement</category>
            <category>feedback</category>
            <category>app renaming</category>
            <category>piracy</category>
            <category>alternative sources</category>
            <category>source-available</category>
            <category>development</category>
            <category>marketing</category>
            <category>financial support</category>
            <category>community</category>
            <category>blog</category>
            <category>Discord</category>
            <category>Subreddit</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Crackpipe 🚀 - The self-hosted gaming platform for DRM-free games]]></title>
            <link>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/01/</link>
            <guid>https://gamevau.lt/blog/2023/07/01/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hey Guys,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey Guys,</p><p>Our team has been working tirelessly for the past year on creating Crackpipe, the source-available, self-hosted, and free alternative to traditional cloud-based game platforms like Steam, Origin, Epic Games, and GoG. We are excited to share that Crackpipe is now available for everyone to use, and we are delighted to disclose it to the community.</p><p>With Crackpipe, you can play and track games together with your friends on a shared file server, free from any restrictions that traditional game platforms may impose. We have designed it to work with DRM-free games, providing a unique solution for those who want a more flexible and open approach to gaming. Think of it like Jellyfin, but for Videogames.</p><p>Crackpipe offers a self-hosted approach that gives you complete control over your gaming experience. The platform enables you to browse your server's game collection, securely download games, launch and play them, and even track your playtimes and progress - regardless of whether the server is offline. Additionally, you can compare stats and play states with other users on the server.</p><p>Our server features offer automatic indexing of games on the file system into a database, enrichment of games with metadata like tags and genres using RAWG API, multi-user authentication, and configurable logging. We have also implemented health monitoring, full-text search, filters, sorting, pagination, and a fully documented API. The Crackpipe platform is highly configurable to suit your needs.</p><p>We are thrilled that you have found us, and we invite you to try Crackpipe today. We would be grateful for any contributions, feedback, bug reports, and feature requests you might have. You can also support us by donating using the "Buy us a Coffee" link on our website. If you have any questions or would like to connect with other Crackpipe users, please join our Discord, Reddit and Lemmy communities - links to which are available in the footer.</p><p>We are passionate about creating a gaming experience that is more open, flexible, and enjoyable for everyone. We hope you will join us on this journey and experience the benefits of a truly source-available alternative to traditional game platforms with Crackpipe.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>gaming</category>
            <category>Crackpipe</category>
            <category>source-available</category>
            <category>self-hosted</category>
            <category>alternative</category>
            <category>cloud-based game platforms</category>
            <category>DRM-free games</category>
            <category>file server</category>
            <category>multi-user authentication</category>
            <category>metadata</category>
            <category>RAWG API</category>
            <category>health monitoring</category>
            <category>API</category>
            <category>Discord server</category>
            <category>Reddit forum</category>
            <category>Lemmy forum</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>